Otja Tjitunga

Mobile number: 07456303500

Email address:

otjitunga@icloud.com

## **Personal Statement:**

I am a friendly and easy going person full of laughter and love. After studying wildlife media and obtaining a degree qualification of 2:1, my studies have equipped me with valuable skills and knowledge on animal behaviour and how the media industry operates which allows me to take on my next role with confidence and enthusiasm. My colleagues note how approachable and personable I am, and how empathically I work with others. I can communicate my ideas using accessible languages, this means that my work can be understood by individuals from a range of backgrounds and reach a wider range of communities.

The degree I attained has been crucial to my social media usage, through the images taken of wildlife I've been able to tap into the world of social media. Utilising apps such as Instagram, Facebook, twitter; YouTube and LinkedIn has helped increase my social media audience.

#### **Education:**

University of Cumbria: BSc Wildlife Media

Grade Obtained: 2:1

Years: 2018-2021

Key skills gained:

- Animal behaviour I learned about animal behaviour and how to observe wild animals which is crucial in wildlife filmmaking as it allows you to know more about the subject you are filming and to be able to predict their behaviour. This allows me to intercept where the best place would be to place the camera to get the best composition and lighting as you cannot direct wild animals.
- Camera skills I learned how to operate cameras on manual settings and how different cameras operates which is important because this skill allows me to be able to operate most cameras as I'm confident in dialling in the settings that will allow me to get a well composed image.

- Editing I learned the foundation of editing and the different type of edit techniques used in the professional media industry and the type of editing programs used such as DaVinci resolve. As editing also includes technical and IT skills, I'm confident with arranging data into folders that is easy for others to access.
- Photography I learned the fundamentals of photography and how to use composition for still or moving images that aid in bringing the story to life.
   This also includes using different techniques or equipment to capture close ups, wide shots and mid shots to form sequences.
- Story telling I learned the importance of story telling and how a great story is the core foundation of a great film and how a compelling story can evoke different emotions.

Easton and Otley College: Level 3 Animal Management

Grade Obtained: Merit

Years: 2016-2018

### Additional Skills:

- CAA certified drone pilot
- Experience working with gimbals such as the Dji rsc2
- Time-lapse
- Shooting 4K and high frame rates

# Work experience

- Farm: I have some work experience as I had been working at my
  Grandmother's farm back in Namibia, before moving to England. At the farm
  I used to look after livestock such as horses, donkeys, cattle, goats,
  chickens and sheep.
- College (Stennett equestrian in Felixstowe) 2016-2018: As part of my level 3 Animal Management diploma I did at college I was required to complete 300 hours of work experience. I completed a 1/4 of my hours at blue cross and 3/4 of hours Stennett equestrian in Felixstowe. During the work

placement I picked up lots of skills and knowledge such as managing habitats.

 Care Home 2016-2020: I have also worked in a care home in Felixstowe as a kitchen assistant for the last 3 years. From my time working in the kitchen I have learned and gained lots of knowledge and skills such as the important of engaging with customers, working as a team and always striving to deliver the highest standards in customer service.

## Personal skills

- Punctual
- Transferable Skills
- Reliable
- Patient
- Bilingual
- Creative
- Organisation Skills
- Fast learner
- Good team worker & leader
- Excellent communication skills
- Interpersonal Skills
- Thrives under pressure

### **Interests & Hobbies**

- Natural history
- Photography and videography
- Sports
- Outdoors
- Technology
- Nature documentaries

# **References**

References are available on request.